THIRUMOORTHY

thirumuthammal1297@gmail.com | (+91) 7639833601| https://www.linkedin.com/in/thirumuthammal/

SUMMARY

An enthusiastic, energetic, and hardworking professional with a successful and consistent track record of meeting goals and delivering high-level job performance. A good team player with strong problem-solving, analytical, and organizational skills. Possess 3.5 years of overall experience in software development.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming Languages: C#, TypeScript

Frameworks: .Net 3.1, 5, 6, 8, .Net Core, Angular, ASP.Net Mvc, Entity Framework Core, XUnit, NUnit

Tools: RBMQ, Docker, Swagger, Postman, Git, GitHub Actions, Bitbucket

Databases & Cloud: MSSQL, Mongo DB, Azure, CI/CD

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

FirstSource. Chennai, India

Software Engineer July 2023 - Oct 2024

- Designed and maintained databases using SQL Server to store and manage patient records, appointment details, and other critical healthcare data.
- Developed and implemented WCF services to handle various healthcare operations, including patient registration, appointment scheduling, medical record management, and billing.
- This is mainly the US healthcare domain maintaining the three different projects Patient Management, Advocate Portal, Register Portal.
- These projects manage the patient records, appointment details, and other critical healthcare data.

Flyers Soft. Chennai, India

Junior Software Engineer

Sep 2021 - June 2023

- The edenred Project was mainly handling payroll management.
- Legacy Application Upgraded (WCF to .NET Core 6.0) Honeywell.
- Migrated the existing desktop application into Restful web-app (Client-Server).
- Developed REST APIs using .NET Core 3.1 with C# and microservices.
- Integrated with various backend systems to ensure seamless data flow.
- Migrated REST APIs from WCF to .NET Core 6.0 using C#.
- Wrote unit test cases using XUnit framework and FakeItEasy library.
- Used SonarQube to validate clean code.

Intake. Chennai, India

June 2021 - Aug 2021

- Used SonarOube to validate clean code.
- Developed REST APIs using .NET Core 6.0 with C# and microservices.
- Implemented continuous integration and deployment using Azure DevOps.
- Successfully deployed applications on Azure App Service

EDUCATION

Freelance

- Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Science, Anna University, 2020
- Higher Secondary School, State Board, 2015
- Secondary School, State Board, 2012

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

• Languages: English (Ruent).